Guide to the Democratic Socialists of America Records TAM.105
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Democratic Socialists of America Records
1940-2006
1972-1995
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Democratic Socialists of America
Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee (U.S.)
TAM.105
142.25 Linear Feet in 148 boxes
Democratic Socialists of America (DSA) was founded in 1973 as the Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee and led by Michael Harrington (1928-1989), best known as the author of The Other America (1962) and became DSA upon its merger with the New American Movement (a New Left organization) in 1982. The collection contains administrative records, including convention materials, minutes, correspondence (including that of Michael Harrington), photographs, state and local chapter files, including local publications, membership files, committee, project, and topical files; correspondence and some administrative records of DSA's Youth Section; reports and proceedings of the Socialist International, of which DSA is the U.S. affiliate. The collection also contains published and unpublished writings of Michael Harrington and files relating to his travel and speaking engagements.
Arrangement
Boxes 1-6 have been arranged into like groups. Series XII has only been inventoried.
Scope and Contents note
The collection contains administrative records, including convention materials; minute; photographs; correspondence (including that of Michael Harrington); state and local chapter files, including local publications, membership files, committee, project, and topical files; correspondence and some administrative records of the DSA's Youth Section; reports and proceedings of the Socialist International, of which DSA is the U.S. affiliate; files on the DSA-founded Institute for Democratic Socialism; and files on other labor and left organizations. The collection also contains published and unpublished writings of Michael Harrington and files relating to his travel and speaking engagements. In addition to Harringon, the principal correspondents are national leaders Carl Shier, Jack Clark, Maxine Phillips, and Frank Llewellyn. While we have noted isolated files of Michal Harrington correspondence (in addition to the several boxes consisting exclusively of his correspondence), there is some additional Harrington correspondence scattered thoughout the collection.
Historical/Biographical Note
Democratic Socialists of America (DSA) was founded in 1973 as the Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee (DSOC) and led by Michael Harrington (1928-1989), best known as the author of The Other America (1962) and became the DSA upon its merger with the New American Movement (a New Left youth organization) in 1982. Harrington and others who left the Socialist Party-Social Democratic Foundation over its support of the Vietnam War were among the principal founders of DSOC. DSA established chapters in virtually every state, including chapters at many colleges and universities, worked to build a progressive presence in the Democratic Party through its Democratic Agenda project, worked closely with progressive labor unions and leaders, feminists and others to promote a social democratic agenda and a peaceful foreign policy, and advocated for socialism while strongly criticising Communism. DSA also published Democratic Left, founded the Socialist Scholars Conference (now known as the Left Forum), and established the Insitute for Democratic Socialism. DSA is the U.S. affiliate of the Socialist International.
Related Archival Materials
New American Movement Records (TAM 051)
Michael Harrington Papers (TAM 209)
Maurice Isserman Research Files for The Other American: The Life of Michael Harrington (TAM 239)
Accruals note
Additional accruals are expected.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee; 1980. Additional accessions were donated by the Democratic Socialists of America in 1983, 1984, 1985, and 1989. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 1970.018, 1980.017, NPA 2002.022, and NPA 2006.030.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu, (212) 998-2630 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Correspondence.; Labor unions and socialism |z United States.; Circular letters.; College students |x Political activity |z United States.; Manuscripts (document genre); Manuscripts for publication.; Lectures.; Mailing lists.; Socialism -- United States -- History.; Socialism -- United States -- Periodicals.; Speeches.; Socialism -- United States.; Proceedings.; Audiocassettes.; Socialism and youth -- United States.; Reports.; Women and socialism -- United States.; Surveys (documents).; Videocassettes.; Poverty |z United States.; Newsletters.; New Left -- United States.; Minutes (administrative records); Shier, Carl; Socialist International (1951- ).; Socialist Party-Social Democratic Federation.; Institute for Democratic Socialism (U.S.).; New American Movement (Organization); Newsletter of the Democratic Left.; Phillips, Maxine; Democratic Socialists of America. Feminist Commission.; Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee. Youth Section; Harrington, Michael, 1928-1989; Democratic Party (U.S.).; Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee (U.S.); Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee. Youth Section; Democratic Socialists of America. Democratic Agenda.; Democratic National Convention |d (1980: |c New York, N.Y.).; Democratic National Convention |d (1976: |c New York, N.Y.).; Democratic left.; Clark, Jack, 1949-; Democratic Socialists of America; Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee (U.S.)
- Series I: Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee
  - Michael Harrington, Correspondence, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Michael Harrington, Correspondence, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Michael Harrington, Correspondence, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Michael Harrington, Correspondence, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Michael Harrington, Correspondence, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Carl Shier/Coalition Caucus, 1966, 1967, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Carl Shier/Coalition Caucus, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Carl Shier/Coalition Caucus, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Michael Harrington, Writings unpublished, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Michael Harrington, Writings unpublished, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Michael Harrington, Writings unpublished, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Writings of Others, 1971, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Unidentified Writings, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - American Federation of Teachers, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee, Background and Formation clippings, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 15a)
  - New York City Politics, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Speaking Engagements, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 16a)
  - United Auto Workers, Affirmative Action, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Union Democracy Review, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Memorabilia, 1959-1973 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Remarks on Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee, 1959 (Box 1A, Folder 1)
  - Discussion bulletins, 1981 (Box 1A, Folder 2)
  - 7 Press releases, 1973, 1976 (Box 1A, Folder 3)
  - Convention diary, 1975 (Box 1A, Folder 4)
  - Pre Convention memos 6 May 1981 Resolutions, amendments (Box 1A, Folder 5)
  - Reports, correspondence, agenda, May 1981 (Box 1A, Folder 7)
  - Reports, correspondence, agenda, May 1981 (Box 1A, Folder 8)
  - Convention memos, appointments, May 1981 (Box 1A, Folder 9)
  - Workshops correspondence, topics, May 1981 (Box 1A, Folder 10)
  - At large delegate correspondence, May 1981 (Box 1A, Folder 11)
  - Memos, proposed amendments, resolutions, report, rules, NAM/Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee document, Jan 1980 (Box 1A, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, resolutions, amendments, agenda, memos, reports, correspondence, Jun 1980 (Box 1A, Folder 13)
  - Youth and Peace Work reports, Jun 1980 (Box 1A, Folder 14)
  - Minutes, resolutions, amendments, Jan 1981 (Box 1A, Folder 15)
  - Minutes, reports, constitution, resolutions, amendments, agendas, 1979-1981 (Box 1A, Folder 16)
  - Key list memos, proposal, clippings, 1979-1981 (Box 1A, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, memos, institutions list, conference program, notices, pamphlet, songs, 1979-1981 (Box 1A, Folder 18)
  - Summer mailing lists, correspondence, 1980 (Box 1A, Folder 19)
  - Summer Youth Conference correspondence, list of participants, 1980 (Box 1A, Folder 20)
  - Days of Decision publications, 1980-1981 (Box 1A, Folder 21)
  - International Union of Socialist Youth trip applications, fundraising letters, 1981 (Box 1A, Folder 22)
  - Minutes, agenda, correspondence, 1980 (Box 1A, Folder 23)
  - Draft resolutions, reports, memos, correspondence, statement, 1981 (Box 1A, Folder 24)
  - Minutes, correspondence, reports, Mar 1980 (Box 1A, Folder 25)
  - Minutes, correspondence, reports, memos, notices, agendas, draft resolutions, Oct 1981 (Box 1A, Folder 26)
  - Program committees: memos, correspondence, statements, form letters, 1980-1981 (Box 1A, Folder 27)
  - Subcommittee meetings: agendas, statements, resolutions, amendments, recommendations, 1980 (Box 1A, Folder 28)
  - Democratic Agenda Conference: bulletin, reports, 1979-1980 (Box 1A, Folder 29)
  - Education Task Force: memos, correspondence, readings lists, 1977 (Box 1A, Folder 30)
  - Health Care Task Force: newsletter and subscription form, bibliography, 1980 (Box 1A, Folder 31)
  - Hispanic Commission: reports, correspondence, memos, newsletters, 1977-1978 (Box 1A, Folder 32)
  - Industrial Democracy Task Force: essay, bibliographies, correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 1A, Folder 33)
  - Jewish Commission: proposal, 1981 (Box 1A, Folder 34)
  - Lawyer`s Caucus: letter, Mar 1978 (Box 1A, Folder 35)
  - Committee on Religion and Socialism: newsletters, correspondence, activists list, 1978-1979 (Box 1A, Folder 36)
  - Temporary Interim Committee: minutes, Aug, Oct 1981 (Box 1A, Folder 37)
  - Records: Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee Formation and Early Years: Carl Shier Correspondence, 1971-1978 (Box 1B)
  - Election to Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee Convention, 1975 (Box 1C, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence and Mailing List, Circa 1979 (Box 1C, Folder 2)
  - Michael Harrington as Delegate to Interim Convention of Democratic Party, 1974 (Box 1C, Folder 3)
  - Michael Harrington: Open Letter to Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee, Jun 1973 (Box 1C, Folder 4)
  - Key List, 1974-1975 (Box 1C, Folder 5)
  - Representative Larry McDonald on Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee, 1978 (Box 1C, Folder 6)
  - Membership Reports, 1975-1976 (Box 1C, Folder 7)
  - Midwest Labor Conference, 1973-1974, 1976 (Box 1C, Folder 8)
  - Minority Recruitment, 1977 (Box 1C, Folder 8A)
  - National Alliance Against Racism, 1973-1977 (Box 1C, Folder 9)
  - National Board, Oct 12, 1973 (Box 1C, Folder 10)
  - National Board, Feb 14, 1974 - May 19, 1974 (Box 1C, Folder 11)
  - National Board, Mar 1975 (Box 1C, Folder 12)
  - National Board, Dec 13, 1975 (Box 1C, Folder 13)
  - National Board, 1974-1976 (Box 1C, Folder 14)
  - National Board, Mar 13, 1976 (Box 1C, Folder 15)
  - National Board, 1977 (Box 1C, Folder 16)
  - National Board, 1978 (Box 1C, Folder 17)
  - National Board, 1979 (Box 1C, Folder 18)
  - National Office Committee/National Steering Committee, 1973 (Box 1C, Folder 19)
  - National Office Committee, 1974 (Box 1C, Folder 20)
  - National Office Committee, 1975 (Box 1C, Folder 21)
  - National Office Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 1C, Folder 22)
  - National Office Committee, 1978 (Box 1D, Folder 1)
  - Organizers Institute, Undated (Box 1D, Folder 2)
  - Olaf Palme Reception, Oct 17, 1975 (Box 1D, Folder 3)
  - Puerto Rico, 1977-1978 (Box 1D, Folder 4)
  - Public Events, 1975 (Box 1D, Folder 5)
  - Portugal Mailgram Campaign, Jul 1975-Aug 1975 (Box 1D, Folder 6)
  - Portugal Rights Defense Fund, 1976 (Box 1D, Folder 7)
  - Socialist Filmstrip, 1975-1976 (Box 1D, Folder 8)
  - Socialist Weekends, 1973-1975 (Box 1D, Folder 9)
  - Soviet Jewry (Political Prisoners), 1977-1979 (Box 1D, Folder 10)
  - Speakers Bureau, 1975 (Box 1D, Folder 11)
  - Staff Meetings, 1976-1977 (Box 1D, Folder 12)
  - Staff Meetings, 1978 (Box 1D, Folder 13)
  - Staff Meetings, 1979 (Box 1D, Folder 14)
  - Stencils, Form Letters, Undated (Box 1D, Folder 15)
  - J.P Stevens Campaign, 1975-1978 (Box 1D, Folder 16)
  - Youth Conference Registrations, 1975 (Box 1D, Folder 17)
- Series II: Organizational Overview
  - Remarks on Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Discussion bulletins, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 7 Press releases, 1973, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Series III: Conventions
  - Convention diary, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Pre Convention memos 6 May 1981 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Reports, correspondence, agenda Resolutions, amendments, May 1981 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
  - Convention memos, appointments, May 1981 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Workshops correspondence, topics, May 1981 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - At large delegate correspondence, May 1981 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Series IV: National Board
  - Memos, proposed amendments, resolutions, report, rules, NAM/Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee document, Jan 1980 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, resolutions, amendments, agenda, memos, reports, correspondence, Jun 1980 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Youth and Peace Work reports, Jun 1980 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Minutes, resolutions, amendments, Jan 1981 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Series V: Youth Section
  - Minutes, reports, constitution, resolutions, amendments, agendas, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Key list memos, proposal, clippings, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, memos, institutions list, conference program, notices, pamphlet, songs, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Summer mailing lists, correspondence, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Summer Youth Conference correspondence, list of participants, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Days of Decision publications, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - International Union of Socialist Youth trip applications, fundraising letters, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Series VI: National Executive Committee (NEC)
  - Minutes, agenda, correspondence, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Draft resolutions, reports, memos, correspondence, statement, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Minutes, correspondence, reports, Mar 1981 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Minutes, correspondence, reports, memos, notices, agendas, draft resolutions, Oct 1981 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Series VII: Commissions, Committees, Task Forces, Caucuses and Projects
  - Program committees: memos, correspondence, statements, form letters, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Subcommittee meetings: agendas, statements, resolutions, amendments, recommendations, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Democratic Agenda Conference: bulletin, reports, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Education Task Force: memos, correspondence, readings lists, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Health Care Task Force: newsletter and subscription form, bibliography, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Hispanic Commission: reports, correspondence, memos, newsletters, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Industrial Democracy Task Force: essay, bibliographies, correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Jewish Commission: proposal, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Lawyer`s Caucus: letter, Mar 1978 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Committee on Religion and Socialism: newsletters, correspondence, activists list, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Temporary Interim Committee: minutes, Aug, Oct 1981 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Series VIII: Locals, State and Regional Organizations
  - Alabama: correspondence, notices, 1980-1982 (Box 2A, Folder 1)
  - Alaska: correspondence, notice, clippings, 1980-1981 (Box 2A, Folder 2)
  - California: resolution, clippings, 1979-1980 (Box 2A, Folder 3)
  - California, Bay Area: form letters, correspondence, proposal, report, calendars, notices, 1978-1981 (Box 2A, Folder 4)
  - California, Los Angeles: minutes, report, correspondence, 1980-1982 (Box 2A, Folder 5)
  - California, Sacramento Valley: correspondence, notices, clippings, song, 1978-1980 (Box 2A, Folder 6)
  - California, San Diego: minutes, correspondence, notices, clippings, agendas, 1979-1981 (Box 2A, Folder 7)
  - California, Santa Cruz: report, publication, clipping, 1981-1982 (Box 2A, Folder 8)
  - Colorado: correspondence, bulletin, 1979-1980 (Box 2A, Folder 9)
  - Connecticut: correspondence, notices, clippings, 1980-1982 (Box 2A, Folder 10)
  - D.C., Washington: correspondence, memos, report, clippings, 1979-1982 (Box 2A, Folder 11)
  - Florida: correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 2A, Folder 12)
  - Georgia: correspondence, 1979-1981 (Box 2A, Folder 13)
  - Georgia, Atlanta: constitution, letter, 1980 (Box 2A, Folder 14)
  - Illinois: correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 2A, Folder 15)
  - Illinois, Chicago: correspondence, report, clippings, 1978-1981 (Box 2A, Folder 16)
  - Illinois, Champaign Urbana: correspondence, notices, 1980 (Box 2A, Folder 17)
  - Illinois, Springfield: correspondence, 1980 (Box 2A, Folder 18)
  - Indiana: correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 2A, Folder 19)
  - Iowa: correspondence, notices, 1979-1981 (Box 2A, Folder 20)
  - Kansas: correspondence, 1980 (Box 2A, Folder 21)
  - Kentucky: correspondence, clippings, 1980-1982 (Box 2A, Folder 22)
  - Louisiana: correspondence, 1980 (Box 2A, Folder 23)
  - Maine: correspondence, 1980, 1982 (Box 2A, Folder 24)
  - Maryland: correspondence, 1980 (Box 2A, Folder 25)
  - Massachusetts: correspondence, invitation, 1980-1981 (Box 2A, Folder 26)
  - Mass., Boston: correspondence, clippings, notice, pamphlet, 1980-1982 (Box 2A, Folder 27)
  - Michigan: correspondence, notices, pamphlets, 1979-1982 (Box 2A, Folder 28)
  - Minnesota: correspondence, memos, clipping, 1980-1982 (Box 2A, Folder 29)
  - Mississippi: correspondence, 1980 (Box 2A, Folder 30)
  - Missouri: correspondence, notices, 1980-1982 (Box 2A, Folder 31)
  - New Hampshire: correspondence, 1980 (Box 2A, Folder 32)
  - New Jersey: correspondence, notice, 1980-1981 (Box 2A, Folder 33)
  - New Mexico: correspondence, 1980 (Box 2A, Folder 34)
  - New York Albany, Ithaca: annual report, correspondence, notice, 1981-1982 (Box 2A, Folder 35)
  - New York, Nassau County: correspondence, notices, statement of principles, clippings, 1980, 1982 (Box 2A, Folder 36)
  - New York, New York City: correspondence, memos, statements, notices, pamphlets, 1978-1981 (Box 2A, Folder 37)
  - New York, Rochester: annual report, correspondence, notices, invoices, 1980-1981 (Box 2A, Folder 38)
  - New York, Suffolk County: correspondence, clipping, notices, 1980-1981 (Box 2A, Folder 39)
  - North Carolina: correspondence, notice, 1979-1982 (Box 2A, Folder 40)
  - Ohio: correspondence, memos, 1980-1981 (Box 2A, Folder 41)
  - Oregon: annual report, correspondence, resolution, memos, clippings, poster ad, 1980-1982 (Box 2A, Folder 42)
  - Pennsylvania: correspondence, memos, notices, brochures, 1979-1981 (Box 2A, Folder 43)
  - Rhode Island: annual report, correspondence, notices, 1979-1982 (Box 2A, Folder 44)
  - Tennessee: correspondence, memos, schedule, 1979-1982 (Box 2A, Folder 45)
  - Texas: correspondence, membership roster, report, notices, clipping, 1979-1982 (Box 2A, Folder 46)
  - Vermont: minutes, correspondence, notices, clippings, 1980-1981 (Box 2A, Folder 47)
  - Virginia: correspondence, constitution, bylaws; 1982-19-19report, notices, 1979-1980 (Box 2A, Folder 48)
  - Washington state: annual report, preamble, correspondence, memos, notices, clippings, 1979-1982 (Box 2A, Folder 49)
  - Wisconsin: correspondence, notices, news release, clipping newsletters:, 1980-1981 (Box 2A, Folder 50)
  - Grass Roots, Oct 1977-Jun 1978 (Box 2A, Folder 51)
  - California: Bay Area, 1976-1977, 1979 (Box 2A, Folder 52)
  - California, Los Angeles, 1978-1981 (Box 2A, Folder 53)
  - Colorado, 1980 (Box 2A, Folder 54)
  - Illinois, Champaign-Urbana, 1979-1982 (Box 2A, Folder 55)
  - D.C., Washington, 1977-1982 (Box 2B, Folder 1)
  - Illinois, Chicago, 1976-1980 (Box 2B, Folder 2)
  - Maine, 1976, 1979-1980 (Box 2B, Folder 3)
  - Maryland, 1978, 1982 (Box 2B, Folder 4)
  - Massachusetts, 1976-1977 (Box 2B, Folder 5)
  - Michigan, 1978-1982 (Box 2B, Folder 6)
  - Minnesota, 1978-1981 (Box 2B, Folder 7)
  - Missouri, 1979-1981 (Box 2B, Folder 8)
  - New England, 1979 (Box 2B, Folder 9)
  - New Jersey, 1979 (Box 2B, Folder 10)
  - New York Albany, Ithaca, Rochester, 1981-1982 (Box 2B, Folder 11)
  - New York Nassau County, 1977-1979 (Box 2B, Folder 12)
  - New York Suffolk County, 1978 (Box 2B, Folder 13)
  - Oregon, 1977-1978 (Box 2B, Folder 14)
  - Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, 1978-1981 (Box 2B, Folder 15)
  - Pennsylvania, Pittsburgh, 1978 (Box 2B, Folder 16)
  - Virginia, 1981-1982 (Box 2B, Folder 17)
  - Wisconsin, 1981-1982 (Box 2B, Folder 18)
- Series IX: Administrative Files
  - Staff meetings minutes, memos, 1978-1980 (Box 2B, Folder 19)
  - Key list memos, 1981 (Box 2B, Folder 20)
  - Debs Thomas dinner form letters, 1981 (Box 2B, Folder 21)
  - General form letters, dues reminders, registration form, 1978-1979 (Box 2C, Folder 23)
  - Personnel and Management Committee memo / application for National Director, 1980 (Box 2C, Folder 24)
  - Time diary, Nov 8-14, 1980 (Box 2C, Folder 25)
  - Travel schedules, 1980-1981 (Box 2C, Folder 26)
  - Fundraising activities, correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 2C, Folder 27)
- Series X: Clippings
  - News clippings, letter, calendar, 1977-1981 (Box 2C, Folder 28)
- Series XI: Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee and New American Movement Conventions and Joint Publications
  - Convention agenda, Aug 1979 (Box 2C, Folder 29)
  - New American Movement Convention resolutions, amendments, general information, factsheet, report, chapter membership data, candidacy statements, form letter, song sheet, Jul 1980 (Box 2C, Folder 30)
  - Letter, questionnaire, bulletin, pamphlet, memo, 1980-1981 (Box 2C, Folder 31)
- Series XII: Unprocessed
  - Records: Michael Harrington Correspondence, 1971-May 1979 (Box 3)
  - Records: Michael Harrington Correspondence, Jun 1979-May 1982 (Box 4)
  - Records: Michael Harrington Correspondence, Jun 1982-Jan 1987; General Correspondence, Jul 1979-Jun 1979, 1975-1987 (Box 5)
  - Records: General Correspondence, Jul 1979-Jan 1983; "General Correspondence" with State and Local Chapters, 1972-1973 (Enumerated in note below), 1972-Jan 1983 (Box 6)
    Scope and Content Note
    General Correspondence: Long Island, 1973-1974
    General Correspondence: Minnesota, 1974-1975
    General Correspondence: Mississippi, 1974
    General Correspondence: Montana, 1974
    General Correspondence: New Hampshire, 1972-1975
    General Correspondence: New Jersey, 1974-1975
    General Correspondence: New Mexico, 1973-1974
    General Correspondence: New York City, 1973-1976 (two folders)
    Meeting Notes: New York City, 1973-1975
    General Correspondence: New York Local DSOC Steering Committee Minutes, 1973
    General Correspondence: New York State, 1971-1975 (four folders)
    General Correspondence: North Carolina, 1973-1975
    General Correspondence: Ohio, 1973-1975 (three folders)
    General Correspondence: Oklahoma, 1973-1974
    General Correspondence: Tennessee, 1975